Oleksandr Pikuza

PERSONAL DATA

ORIGIN: Chernihiv, Ukraine

DATE OF BIRTH: July 14, 1988
PHONE: +380 63 1582832

SKYPE: +380 63 1582832 alexandro.cn.ua

EMAIL: oleksandr.pikuza@gmail.com

JOB OBJECTIVE

Looking for Python developer position. Prefer remote job opportunities

SUMMARY

Software engineer with extensive experience of Python.

Python developer with 5 years of IT industry experience. Has an experience of leadership (6 Python developers team).

Has background in software engineering, web development. Responsible of system architecture and infrastructure design.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nov. 2014 - Present Python developer at Svitla Systems, Work remotely

 Monitoring system in the field of Oil and Gas Industry that provides engineers with an intuitive modeling environment to track operation modes within the sensors of any given asset. System allows experienced operators to embed knowledge and automate key decision processes regarding the operation of complex machines.

MAY 2012 - Nov. 2014 Python developer / Team Lead at JBS, Chernihiv

- System simmillar to CMS which is used for creating web portals and self-services in the field of telecommunication. Created products' structure consists of pages with number of a blocks with content. Pages and blocks are managed via administrative interface without any manipulation by the administrators. Interaction to obtain an information from a billing web services about displayed services/promotions and its order occurs through a SOAP protocol
- Online service for aggregation of restaurants, hotels, posters and billboards tagged by customer rating and feedbacks. Including search with complex conditions and social networks integration

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED FROM PREVIOUS PAGE)

OCT. 2010 - MAY 2012 Python developer / Team Lead at YuktiGroup, Chernihiv

- Daozon.ru B2b a trading platform where suppliers from China represent their goods for Russian business owners
- Sambuka.me Online service for ordering photo albums. Includes online editor for images/photos and API for offline integration with printing house, automation of ts processes such as printing, assembly and delivery of user albums

DEC. 2007 - Nov. 2008 Software Developer at Softline, Chernihiv

 Software developer for financial system (reports, forms, scripts) of Ministry of finance of Ukraine. Using Oracle Hyperion Planning

EDUCATION AND TRAININGS

2009 - 2010 Chernihiv State Technological University, Chernihiv
Specialization: Specialized computer systems (SPECIALIST DEGREE)

Chernihiv State Technological University, Chernihiv
Specialization: Specialized computer systems (BACHELOR'S DEGREE)

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND FRAMEWORKS

Python / Django | The main language which I'm using in work process, above all in web-development (with Django framework) but also in programming watchdogs, scripts for deploying/updating servers.

JavaScript | Commonly used in work process.

Ruby / RoR | Basic knowledge. But to learn it is interesting for me. Use mainly for funny/pet projects.

Lisp It's my goal #1 to learn it. Once I liked its ideology "Programmable programming language". Every time I face it - like more and more.

PLATFORMS AND TECHNOLOGIES

Linux / Unix | Extensive using of Linux both for personal and enterprise use

(distributions: RHEL, CentOS, Ubuntu). Also MacOS X for personal use

at laptop

Libraries | FeinCMS, DjanfoCMS, Jinja, Celery, South, Alembic, Haystack

Databases | MySQL, PostrgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis

Deployment | Vagrant, Puppet, Ansible, Fabric, Jenkins

Bug tracking | Jira, Basecamp, Redmine, Trello

Revision Control | Used CVS at University, SVN both at University and work, Git and Mer-

curial at work

CERTIFICATES

Oct. 2012 - Dec. 2012 M101, MongoDB for Developers

Certificate

LANGUAGES

Ukrainian mothertongue Russian mothertongue English proficient

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES